const british = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "What is the highest mountain in Great Britain?",
        answer: "ben nevis",
        hint: "Located in Scotland"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which city has the nickname the ‘city of dreaming spires’?",
        answer: "oxford",
        hint: "Home to Magdalen College"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "Catatonia are a famous band from Wales, but who is their lead singer?",
        answer: "cerys matthews",
        hint: "Born 11 April 1969"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "Which of the following cities is the furthest north: Leeds, Liverpool or Manchester?",
        answer: "leeds",
        hint: "Home to the Royal Armouries houses"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "The Suffolk Punch is a breed of which animal?",
        answer: "horse",
        hint: "These animals were domesticated on the plains of northern Kazakstan over 5000 years ago"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "What is the most common street name in Great Britain? ",
        answer: "high street",
        hint: "Typically where most shops are located in towns and villages"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "Which village in Wales shares its name with a term meaning to ‘say something indistinctly and quietly’?",
        answer: "mumbles",
        hint: "Located in the county of Swansea"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "Which is the only town in England with a name ending with an exclamation mark?",
        answer: "westward ho!",
        hint: "Located in Devon"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "Which 13th-century Scottish warrior did Mel Gibson play in the 1995 film Braveheart?",
        answer: "william wallace",
        hint: "Layed to rest in London"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "The River Severn is the longest river in Britain at 354 km, but which is the second longest?",
        answer: "river thames",
        hint: "Famous for running through London"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Which famous jazz club has the address 47 Frith Street, London?",
        answer: "Ronnie Scott",
        hint: "Located in Soho"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "In which county would you find the White Cliffs of Dover?",
        answer: "kent",
        hint: "Couny located in the South-east of england"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Who was the first monarch to use Buckingham Palace as their official residence?",
        answer: "queen victoria",
        hint: "These royal adopted the title Empress of India on 1st May 1876"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "8 Ball, Easy Peeler and Clockwork Tangerine are all types of British what?",
        answer: "craft beer",
        hint: "popular alcaholic drink"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "What is the national flower of Wales?",
        answer: "daffodil",
        hint: "Yellow and spring flowering."
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "What is the capital city of Scotland?",
        answer: "edinburgh",
        hint: "Affectionatly nicknamed Auld Reekie"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "Which metal shares its name with a famous London theatre? ",
        answer: "palladium",
        hint: "These theatre is located in Soho London"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "Alnwick Castle was used as the exterior shots in which film series? ",
        answer: "harry potter",
        hint: "A popular childs book by JK Rowling"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "What was 32 inches in 1512, 35 inches by the 1520s, and then 54 inches in 1545?",
        answer: "King Henry VIII’s waist",
        hint: "This King is famous for this attribute"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Which mountain range is often described as the ‘backbone of England’?",
        answer: "The Pennines",
        hint: "The highest point is Cross Fell"
    }

]

export default british;